const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following correctly describes Kussmaul's sign?","answers":[{"option":"Paradoxical drop in the jugular venous pressure during expiration","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical rise of the pulse rate during inspiration","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical rise in the jugular venous pressure during expiration","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical rise in the jugular venous pressure during inspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Paradoxical drop in the jugular venous pressure during inspiration","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which antianginal drug will not be given to a patient with a history of migraines?","answers":[{"option":"Statin","bool":false},{"option":"Amlodipine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitroglycerin","bool":true},{"option":"Nifedipine","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is an intravenous vasodilator?","answers":[{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Diazoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Hydralazine","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium nitroprusside","bool":true},{"option":"Minoxidil","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Acute pericarditis is most commonly caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fungus","bool":false},{"option":"Virus","bool":true},{"option":"Acute myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Post infarction syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteria","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"P-mitrale is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Left ventricle atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrial enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricle atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrial enlargement","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is the valve area in severe aortic stenosis?","answers":[{"option":"Less than 1 cm²","bool":true},{"option":"2.6-3.5 cm²","bool":false},{"option":"1-1.4 cm²","bool":false},{"option":"1.5-2 cm²","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 0.5 cm²","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A patient with aortic stenosis having symptoms of angina will survive how many years without surgery?","answers":[{"option":"6 years","bool":false},{"option":"3 years","bool":false},{"option":"5 years","bool":true},{"option":"2 years","bool":false},{"option":"1 year","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common silent valvular abnormality?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve prolapse","bool":true},{"option":"Libman sack endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Infective endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most common tumor of blood vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Pyogenic granuloma","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioendothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":true},{"option":"Glomus tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"In which condition is there a difference in blood pressure between both the arms?","answers":[{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Supravalvular aortic stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Subvalvular aortic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A right ventricular myocardial infarction is caused by the occlusion of which artery?","answers":[{"option":"Left circumflex artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior descending artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right coronary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Left coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"The lipoprotein subfraction associated with the term “good” cholesterol is:","answers":[{"option":"High density lipoprotein (HDL)","bool":true},{"option":"Very low density lipoprotein (VLDL)","bool":false},{"option":"Low density lipoprotein (LPL)","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicron (CM)","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate density lipoprotein (IDL)","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Phenytoin, an epileptic drug, is a useful antiarrhythmic agent because:","answers":[{"option":"Ability to facilitate the Na extrusion","bool":false},{"option":"Efficacy in wide range of ventricular arrhythmias","bool":false},{"option":"Membrane stabilizing influence","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium channel blocking effect","bool":false},{"option":"Depresses the automaticity in ventricular purkinje fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following are minor manifestations of rheumatic fever according to Jones criteria?","answers":[{"option":"Jaundice and edema","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and elevated erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR)","bool":true},{"option":"Migratory polyarthritis, carditis, subcutaneous nodules, erythema marginatum, Sydenham chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Purpuric rash and cough","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What does lidocaine do?","answers":[{"option":"Reduce action potential duration","bool":true},{"option":"Increase action potential duration","bool":false},{"option":"Increase PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease conductivity","bool":false},{"option":"Increase the amplitude of QRS complex","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Most common cause of myocarditis is:","answers":[{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Borrelia","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Rickettsia","bool":false},{"option":"Coxsackievirus","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is seen in the tetralogy of Fallot?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricular hypertrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Left ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which congenital heart disease has the characteristic feature of a continuous murmur?","answers":[{"option":"Coarctation of the aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":true},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent truncus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Cinchonism is an adverse effect of which of the following drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Quinidine","bool":true},{"option":"Procainamide","bool":false},{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of death in myocardial infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular wall rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiogenic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular fibrillation","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the pathogenesis of Dressler syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Invasion of microorganisms","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic extension","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune","bool":true},{"option":"Seeding from the blood","bool":false},{"option":"Direct introduction during cardiotomy","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which cardiac dysfunction is seen in restrictive cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Systolic dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Diastolic dysfunction","bool":true},{"option":"It has no effect on systolic or diastolic function of heart","bool":false},{"option":"Both systolic and diastolic dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Systolic dysfunction that converts to diastolic with increasing severity","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which autoimmune disease presents necrotizing granulomatous inflammation and pauci-immune vasculitis?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Wegener granulomatosis","bool":true},{"option":"Grave's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune myocarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following refers to any congenital heart defect that leads to pulmonary hypertension, cyanosis, right ventricular hypertrophy, and reversal of flow?","answers":[{"option":"Ebstein anamoly","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Aortitis","bool":false},{"option":"Eisenmenger syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the cause of a double apical beat/impulse?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of dilated cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic","bool":true},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery disease","bool":false},{"option":"Genetics","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the mechanism of action of heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Increases cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks protein kinase A","bool":false},{"option":"Increases cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases hepatic synthesis of vitamin K dependent factors","bool":false},{"option":"Catalyzes the binding of antithrombin III","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"90 percent alcohol is converted into:","answers":[{"option":"Formalin","bool":false},{"option":"Water and CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid and acetaldehyde","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaldehyde","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A young male with a history of joint pain and fever when he was fifteen now has a systolic murmur. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infective bacterial endocarditis resulting in mitral regurgitation","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myocardial infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following agents can cause infective endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus bovis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is another name for red infarcts?","answers":[{"option":"Coagulative infarcts","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous infarcts","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic infarcts","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculous infarcts","bool":false},{"option":"Anemic infarcts","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Crescentic glomerulonephritis and hemoptysis with a raised cytoplasmic antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibody (c-ANCA) level best describe which type of vasculitis?","answers":[{"option":"Henoch-Schonlein purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Churg-Strauss syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomatosis with polyangiitis","bool":true},{"option":"Microscopic polyangiitis","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasture syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most appropriate statement regarding enalapril?","answers":[{"option":"It can cause diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"It causes vasoconstriction of arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"It can be used in pregnant women","bool":false},{"option":"It is a prodrug","bool":true},{"option":"It is eliminated in the feces primarily","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What are the major criteria for the diagnosis of rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Jaundice and edema","bool":false},{"option":"Migratory polyarthritis, carditis, subcutaneous nodules, erythema marginatum, Sydenham chorea","bool":true},{"option":"Purpuric rash and cough","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and elevated erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR)","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most accurate test to detect coronary artery disease?","answers":[{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Percutaneous coronary intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery bypass surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary angiography","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Nitroglycerin is contraindicated in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Renal artery stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Raised intracranial pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertensive emergency","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of mitral valve prolapse?","answers":[{"option":"Myxomatous degeneration","bool":true},{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hydropic degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid valve prolapse","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following agents causes postural hypotension?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrates","bool":true},{"option":"Statins","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Where is angiotensinogen synthesized?","answers":[{"option":"Intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":true},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Red infarct commonly occurs in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Chest pain aggravates on lying flat and improves on sitting up in:","answers":[{"option":"Endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":true},{"option":"Angina","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most commonly affected artery in heart disease?","answers":[{"option":"Right coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior descending artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":true},{"option":"Left circumflex artery","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of abdominal aortic aneurysms?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Vascular wall abnormalities","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculitis","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Atherosclerosis","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A grade 4 murmur is:","answers":[{"option":"Barely audible","bool":false},{"option":"Audible without a stethoscope","bool":false},{"option":"Loud but not accompanied by a thrill","bool":false},{"option":"Loud but with a palpable thrill","bool":true},{"option":"Associated with a thrill","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Suppurative pericarditis with subsequent scarring leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrinous pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive mediastinopericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Serous pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Constrictive pericarditis","bool":true},{"option":"Myopericarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the treatment for warfarin overdose?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Methanol is excreted through:","answers":[{"option":"Feces","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true},{"option":"Sweat","bool":false},{"option":"Eyes","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following electrocardiogram (ECG) changes is seen in hyperkalemia?","answers":[{"option":"Shallow T wave","bool":false},{"option":"ST depression","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of P wave","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular ectopic beats","bool":false},{"option":"U wave","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which drug cannot be given in digitalis toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Digoxin immune FAB","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestyramine","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Colestipol","bool":false},{"option":"Activated charcoal","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Pulse in aortic stenosis is:","answers":[{"option":"Neutralizing","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing","bool":false},{"option":"Decreasing","bool":false},{"option":"Slow rising","bool":true},{"option":"Collapsing","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is an adverse effect of calcium channel blockers that works on the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Convulsions","bool":false},{"option":"Postural hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Constipation","bool":true},{"option":"Dizziness","bool":false},{"option":"Headache","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"V waves in tricuspid regurgitation coincide with:","answers":[{"option":"INC and SVC pressures","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular systole","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial systole","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular diastole","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary wedge pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following antihypertensive drugs causes depression?","answers":[{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Nifedipine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrates","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Reserpine","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a cause of secondary hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Renal artery stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Altered sodium balance","bool":true},{"option":"Primary aldosteronism","bool":false},{"option":"Cushing syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Pheochromocytoma","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is the main indication for coronary artery bypass graft (CABG)?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Double-vessel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Stable angina","bool":false},{"option":"Single vessel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Three-vessel disease","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the characteristic feature of Eisenmenger's syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Presence of cyanosis","bool":false},{"option":"Right to left shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Left to right shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Reversal of blood flow","bool":true},{"option":"Impaired neurological function","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is a modifiable factor of hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":false},{"option":"Ethnicity","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":true},{"option":"Gender","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the drug of choice for the management of digitalis toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Digibind","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrates","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the immediate treatment of bacterial endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin + aminoglycoside","bool":true},{"option":"Amoxicillin+third generation cephalosporin","bool":false},{"option":"Linezolid+Tazobactam","bool":false},{"option":"Third generation cephalosporin","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 55-year-old man is admitted to the hospital following a myocardial infarction. On third day after myocardial infarction, he develops a new pansystolic murmur that radiates to axilla. What is the most likely cause of this murmur?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following can be used to treat Prinzmetal/variant angina?","answers":[{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Rest","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Nitroglycerin","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of death after myocardial infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Interventricular septal rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac tamponade","bool":false},{"option":"Dressler’s syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Arrhythmias","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the etiology of essential hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Polyarteritis nodosa","bool":false},{"option":"Acute glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic","bool":true},{"option":"Sleep apnea","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"In which cardiomyopathy is there systolic dysfunction?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrophic, dilated, and restrictive cardiomyopathies","bool":false},{"option":"Both hypertrophic and dilated cardiomyopathies","bool":false},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 35-year-old woman presents with a high pitched early diastolic murmur. What is the most likely valvular abnormality she is suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":true},{"option":"Both aortic and mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the effect of hypertension on blood vessels out of the following options?","answers":[{"option":"P-ANCA vasculitis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"C-ANCA vasculitis","bool":false},{"option":"Immune-complex mediated vasculitis","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of these is a common cause of acute organic mitral regurgitation?","answers":[{"option":"Papillary muscle rupture","bool":true},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular remodelling","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following electrocardiogram (ECG) changes will he seen in hypokalemia?","answers":[{"option":"Shortened PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"Steeper T wave","bool":false},{"option":"ST elevation","bool":false},{"option":"Appearance of a U wave","bool":true},{"option":"Shortened QT interval","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following are the most severe and prevalent complications of infectious endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Intracardiac abscesses","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic embolizations","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular blocks","bool":false},{"option":"Neurologic sequelae","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Large ventricular septal defects can result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Eisenmenger syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Hypercoagulability","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is the best test for pericarditis?","answers":[{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"CT-scan","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"ECG","bool":true},{"option":"Angiography","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What is a finding on cardiac valves in infective endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Vegetations","bool":true},{"option":"Iron deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomas","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"ST elevation in leads V1-V6 point to occlusion in what artery?","answers":[{"option":"Right circumflex artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left circumflex artery","bool":false},{"option":"Obtuse marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior descending artery","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a prodrug and is used to open K+ channels?","answers":[{"option":"Iblutide","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine","bool":true},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is a relative contraindication of exercise tolerance test (ETT)?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic stenosis (severe)","bool":false},{"option":"Deep vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Untreated severe systemic hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Active myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"What drug is used for the prevention and relief of ischemia?","answers":[{"option":"Sacubitril","bool":false},{"option":"Nitroglycerin","bool":true},{"option":"Simvastatin","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Ranolazine","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"In which of the following conditions does the inward movement of the apex beat during systole occurs?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 5-year-old child is referred for evaluation of suspected heart disease. On inspection of the precordium is hyperdynamic, while apex beat is felt in 6th intercostal space (I.C.S) lateral to the midclavicular line. The most probable cause of these findings is,","answers":[{"option":"Right ventricular enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Biventricular enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricular enlargement","bool":true},{"option":"Right ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of these is a non-modifiable risk factor in the context of cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":true},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 65-year-old man presents to the emergency department with sudden onset of chest pain radiating to his left arm. He is diaphoretic and short of breath. An ECG shows ST-segment elevation in the lateral leads. The patient is diagnosed with acute myocardial infarction involving the lateral wall. What is the most appropriate 'initial' management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Morphine","bool":true},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Percutaneous coronary intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinolytic therapy","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of syncope in the general population?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":false},{"option":"Micturition syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Orthostatic hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Vasovagal (Neurally mediated; reflex) syncope","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of left ventricle dysfunction?","answers":[{"option":"Raised jugular venous pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Ascites and pedal edema","bool":true},{"option":"S3 gallop","bool":false},{"option":"Orthopnea","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of rheumatic heart disease?","answers":[{"option":"Erythema nodosum","bool":true},{"option":"Polyarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Carditis","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous nodules","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most specific marker for ventricular dysfunction?","answers":[{"option":"N-terminal pro–B-type natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP)","bool":true},{"option":"Angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"proBNP","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial natriuretic peptide (ANP)","bool":false},{"option":"Brain natriuretic peptide (BNP)","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following is an odd statement regarding atrial septal defect (ASD)?","answers":[{"option":"Causes fixed splitting of S2","bool":false},{"option":"Shunt reversal and pulmonary hypertension is not a complication","bool":false},{"option":"Most are 'ostium secundum' defects","bool":false},{"option":"One of the most common congenital heart defects","bool":false},{"option":"More common in males","bool":true}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following conditions is not associated with aortic regurgitation?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan’s syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 60-year-old male presents to the emergency department with severe chest pain radiating to the left shoulder for the past hour. He has a history of hypertension and type 2 diabetes mellitus. The patient develops pulmonary edema in the emergency department, and furosemide is given. After the administration, the patient becomes hypotensive with a systolic blood pressure of 70 mmHg. What is the next best step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine infusion","bool":false},{"option":"Administer norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Administer nitroglycerine","bool":false},{"option":"Administer calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Administer dobutamine","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 40-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of intermittent pain in his feet when he moves and often at rest. He is a smoker. On examination, there is erythema and palpable veins on his arms. He is diagnosed with Buerger's disease. Which of the following is the best next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking cessation","bool":true},{"option":"Administer vasodilator medications","bool":false},{"option":"Start systemic corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Initiate anticoagulant therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Refer for surgical revascularization procedures","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 16-year-old girl presents to the clinic with complaints of fever, lethargy, and joint pain for two days. She had an upper respiratory tract illness two weeks ago. On examination, she has firm, painless, small subcutaneous nodules over her elbows. She is diagnosed with rheumatic fever. Which of the following is the recommended period for which you will prescribe her penicillin?","answers":[{"option":"For 1 week","bool":false},{"option":"Until she is 21 years old","bool":true},{"option":"For 2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"For 3 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Until she is 40 years old","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 61-year-old patient presents to the emergency department with acute pulmonary edema. His medical conditions include hypertension and coronary artery disease. He is given high-flow oxygen with continuous positive airway pressure, and IV furosemide is administered. Which of the following should be given next?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous nitroglycerin","bool":true},{"option":"Intravenous morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Noninvasive positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV)","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous sodium bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous dopamine","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"Which of the following drugs are used to control the rate of Wolff-Parkinson-White (WPW) syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Flecainide","bool":true},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"B blocker","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 30-year-old male presents to the emergency department with complaints of palpitations, breathlessness, and fatigue, which started when he was at a bar with his friends. ECG shows irregularly irregular rhythm with a pulse of 130 bpm. Which of the following is the initial drug used for rate control?","answers":[{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Nitroglycerine","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 70-year-old male comes to the emergency department with complaints of chest pain radiating to the left arm for two hours. His ECG shows ST-elevations in leads V4-V6, I, and aVL. Which of the following is the type of infarction depicted by the ECG?","answers":[{"option":"Anterolateral myocardial infarction","bool":true},{"option":"Right ventricular myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior myocardial infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A patient presents to the emergency department with myocardial infarction; suddenly, he develops shortness of breath and hypotension, and no pulse is palpated. An electrocardiogram (ECG) shows broad QRS complexes. Which of the following is the most likely treatment for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) and defibrillation","bool":true},{"option":"Administration of thrombolytic therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous nitroglycerin infusion","bool":false},{"option":"Placement of an intra-aortic balloon pump (IABP)","bool":false},{"option":"Urgent coronary angiography","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2017","question":"A 70-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of blacking out while he is at the barber. He has a history of hypertension. On examination, carotid sinus massage leads to syncope and bradycardia. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Vasovagal syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid hypersensitivity","bool":true},{"option":"Subclavian steel syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Orthostatic hypotension","bool":false}]}]
export default arr